Guide to the Seamen's Friend Society of Wilmington Records, 1810-1963
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Seamen's Friend Society of Wilmington records 1810-1963
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Seamen's Friend Society of Wilmington (Wilmington, N.C.)
0.5 linear feet Extent: 405 Items
RL.01160
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Seamen's Friend Society of Wilmington Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1969 and 1979.
Historical Note
Society located in Wilmington, N.C., that raised money through rental of land and buildings to make anonymous donations to various charities. Dissolved in 1963.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, legal and financial papers, ledger (1853-1923), and memoranda, of a society organized for the improvement of the social, moral, and religious condition of seamen who visited the port of Wilmington, N.C. The society also operated a hospital.
Subject Headings
Seamen's Friend Society of Wilmington (Wilmington, N.C.); Charities -- North Carolina; Merchant mariners -- Missions and charities; Wilmington (N.C.) -- History
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Legal Papers, 1810-1946 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1854-1961
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963
  - Financial Papers, 1855-1941
  - Financial Papers, 1950s
  - Financial Papers, 1960s
  - Legal Papers, 1960-1963
  - Meeting Minutes, 1909-1963
  - Clippings, 1883-1962
  - Ledger, 1853-1923